「纏」　念オーラを 体の周囲に　とどめる技
I have a bad feeling. I feel like I'm missing something.
「絶」　念オーラを完全に絶つ技 自身の気配を消したり 疲労回復に効果がある
There's a gnawing anxiety that won't go away.
いや　お見事。
As they head deeper into NGL in
search of the Chimera Ants' nest, within the Queen's castle, one of the soon-to-be-born
King's three Royal Guards
前の戦いを含め　十分及第だ。
is about to awaken.
いつでも相手になるよ。
What kind of magic did they use?
ヒソカからの 試合の承諾を得たゴンは
And Baro's the one with an iron shell.
戦いに向け　さらなる「念」の修行に 励んでいた
So this is the rare humans' power. Are you worried now?
いよいよ今日から 「発」の修行に入ります。
The king of the jungle's blood
runs through my veins. A few humans can't scare me.
「発」をマスターすれば
Of course...
「念」の基礎は 全て修めたことになります。
Whew, that's a relief.
独自の「念」を 構築して行くだけです。 オス！
I thought I was gonna miss out on tonight's feast. These must be extremely rare humans.
「発」とは オーラを自在に操る技術 つまり　念能力の集大成といえ 次の６つのタイプに大別されます。
We'll tear them to shreds and gobble them down!
オーラを飛ばす「放出系」。 オーラの性質を変える「変化系」。
We're being followed.
オーラを物質化する「具現化系」。
Not from there.
物質や生物を操る「操作系」。
There's quite a number of them.
これら５つとは違う 他に類のない特殊なオーラ これは「特質系」と呼びます。
Listen up... Your job is to distract the enemy,
while attacking from a distance. Do not get too close.
大事なのは　自分に合った能力を 見つけること。 自分に合った？
The 2nd Platoon will take the right, as the 3rd Platoon pincers
them from the left.
主に　２つの才能と 深くつながっています。
My 1st Platoon will trap them,
preventing a rear retreat. Go!
柔軟で　バネのある筋力は 生まれついてのもの。 研ぎ澄まされた五感は
Gon and I didn't notice them.
大自然を遊び場にして 培われたものです。
They're coming from the left and the right.
念能力も　その人が　生まれつき 持っているオーラの性質によって
Keep up your guard.
「六性図」です。 オーラの性質と近いものほど 会得の相性がいい。
Shouldn't we get out of the forest?
生まれ持つオーラが　強化系ならば
This is a trap.
当然　強化系の能力の覚えが 最も早く　力もつきます。
Okay, keep up the chase.
そして隣り合う変化系　放出系も 相性が良いので覚えやすく
Hagya-sama, all goes according to plan.
特質系の能力は非常に覚えにくい。
Good work, Flutter.
あなた方も実際に見た能力で 説明しましょうか。 ヒソカの場合は オーラをゴム状に 変える能力を使っています。
Once we drive our prey into range, one strike with my fangs will finish them.
これは変化系。
This doesn't feel right...
ギドは　独楽と自身の回転力を高め 武器としているので　強化系。 しかし　手元を離れている たくさんの独楽を
Eh? You ordered Flutter to chase the prey, while you hid in the grass to ambush them. That's pretty lame.
武器として使うのは 操作系の能力も要求されるため
Huh? Aren't you the king of the jungle?
相性が悪く いまひとつでしたがね。 そして　カストロ。
A king should face his prey, rather than hiding.
彼の「虎咬拳」は 素晴らしい威力でした。
Just jump out and go,
"Roar! Chomp! Ga ha ha ha!"
極めれば　随一の 使い手となっていたでしょう。
That's so much cooler.
恐らく　彼のオーラは 強化系に属していたはずです。
But you know... This is how the king of the jungle hunts.
しかし　彼は「ダブル」を作る能力を 選んでしまった。
Shut up and watch! Yeah, yeah.
これは　具現化系の能力です。 しかも「ダブル」を操る 操作系の能力も必要とされる。
Well, I don't care, so long as I
get to eat the rare humans.
この２つは　強化系オーラとは 性質的に離れた場所に位置します。
Rare human? What's that?
どちらも強化系とは 相性が悪かったんだね。
I'll explain the details later.
ええ 苦手な能力を会得できたのは
Its number is 4-933. It was captured and brought
in by Zazan's squadron.
たゆまぬ努力と 武芸の才能のたまもの。
Number 4-933...
しかし　その結果 彼は　その才能のほぼ全てを
Doesn't mean a thing to me.
念能力に費やしてしまった。
It was probably given to the Queen.
要するに 選択ミスってことだろ。
Her appetite is even more insatiable these days.
すごい人なのに　残念っす。
She'll give birth to an incredible king.
どうです？　自分の持つ オーラの性質と能力の重要さを
Don't see 'em. It must already be inside the Queen's belly.
理解してもらえましたか？
Are you certain?
オス！ ところでさ
It isn't here...
そもそも　自分のオーラが どの系統に属しているか
Where else would it be? Could it have escaped?
調べる方法なんて　あんの？ あります。
Any creature poisoned by our nerve toxin will be paralyzed for at least a month.
「水見式」　心源流に伝わる オーラの選別法です。
You can't be sure when it
concerns the rare ones. They aren't like normal humans.
「発」の修行としても用いられます。 ここに手を近づけて　「練」を行う。
You should know that very well.
その変化によって 資質を見分けます。
I'm not the same creature I was before.
あっ！ あっ！
The next time I see them, I'll crush them, rip them apart, and eat them.
水が溢れてる。 水の量が変わるのは 強化系の証し。
The antidote I hid in my
back tooth came in handy.
私のオーラが強化系の性質に 属していることを示しています。
But I could barely drag myself across the ground. For the time being, I'll have to hide here...
さっ　３人とも　試してみなさい。
But what's going on?
あっ！ ゴンも強化系かぁ。
Come on, give me a break... I'm busy enough as it is. Didn't you hear me say the Queen
has a huge appetite now?
おっ？ 葉っぱが動いてるっす！
I am well aware of that.
葉が動くのは　操作系の証しです。 お！
I don't know anything about this "rare" stuff, but why are you so obsessed with this human?
よっしゃ　最後は俺だ。
I'd like to ask it a few questions. Can't you see the light surrounding his body?
何も変わんねえぞ。
Then it's true that only some
can identify this power.
そうですねぇ。 葉っぱも動かないし。
Meaning it's a talent.
もしかして　俺って才能ねえ？
Exactly.
いえいえ 水をなめてみてください。 なめる？
This talent is my destiny, bestowed
upon me by the heavens.
あっ　少し甘いかな…。 ホントだ。 確かに　ちょっぴり甘いっす。
The power of a chosen few... If I master this power, I can become the king!
これ　ただの水じゃないの？
I will be king!
今の変化が　より顕著になるよう 鍛錬を続けなさい。 オス！
Retreat! Retreat! Hmm? What's wrong, Flutter?
さぁ　それでは　修行の 成果を見せてもらいましょうか。
Most likely, he was a Squadron Leader.
まずは　キルアくんから。 おう。
I always believed that the world
いいぜ。
That if I brandished them, I could take the life of any other creature, could always satisfy my own hunger...
あっ！ 甘い！ すごい！　蜂蜜みたいだ！
And that I was truly blessed.
よろしい　次はズシ。 オス！
However, that wasn't the case.
んん…！ うっ…！ あっ。
Others were stronger,
so I never could have ruled.
お…　お！
Death taught me that lesson.
ん…！　ぐっ…！
But I am stronger now.
もうしばらく修行が必要ですね。 オス。 次　ゴンくん。 オス！
At the moment, we may not be
strong enough to defeat them.
おっ！ あっ！
We're following them.
あ　ストップ！ ストップ　ゴンくん！
Their nest must be nearby.
あっ　あっ…！　とっと…。 水が増える勢いで グラスに　ヒビが入ってる…
If we follow them, we will find the Queen.
やったね　キルア！ おう！
What is that?
師範代　やっぱり自分は…。 まだまだ修行が必要ですね。
Something is coming!
大事なこと？
That was a fascinating conversation...
ゴン＝フリークスくん 裏ハンター試験　合格！
You mentioned something about talent.
合格ですよ　おめでとう。
Allow me to take part.
裏ハンター試験？ そうです 君は見事に合格しました。
O-One of the Queen's Royal Guards!
念能力の会得は ハンターになるための最低条件。
If I master this power, I can become the king!
なぜなら　プロのハンターには 相応の強さが求められるから。 よこしまな密猟者や 略奪をなりわいとする犯罪者を
I will be the king!
捕らえることは ハンターの基本活動。 犯罪抑止力としての強さが どうしても必要となる。
A short and foolish dream...
…っていうか　ゴンには 教えるつもりだったのかよ。
I am totally outclassed.
ちなみに私が属する 心源流拳法の師範は ネテロ会長ですよ。 えっ！ えっ！ お２人のことは 師範から　いろいろ聞きました。
I can never escape the position
I've been born into...
今の君には十分　資格がありますよ 私が保証します。 まっ　気が向いたらね。
You can relax.
ねぇ　ウイングさん 試験に受かった他の人達が 今　どんなか聞いてる？
Let's talk over there.
ええ。 ハンゾーとクラピカ ２人は別の師範の下
Y-Yes!
すでに「念」を会得しました。
This power is not for me...
ポックルは「練」の習得に 手こずっているようですね。
But for this Royal Guard... And for the King it serves!
レオリオは　医大受験後に 修行を開始するようです。 ちなみに　ヒソカとイルミは 初めから「念」を習得しており
This power is for serving them!
さて　ゴンくん 最後に１つ　忠告です。 えっ？
Impossible...
明日のヒソカとの試合 くれぐれも無理をしないように。
What is that
いいですか？ はい！
evil aura?
ズシ　あなたは　あと４週間 同じ修行です。 オス…。
By the way... Yes? Why is a live human underneath those bones?
皆さん　こんにちは！ 本日　こちらの闘技場では ゴン選手対ヒソカ選手！
There we go. Ah!
注目の一戦が 始まろうとしています！ え ご覧のように　客席は超満員！
"New memories are stored
in the hippocampus, while old memories are kept
in the cerebral cortex.
試合開始前から 異様な熱気に包まれております。
To invoke those memories..."
まだか！ 早く始めろ！
Nyow I understand.
現在４戦して　３勝１敗！ 波に乗っています！
To summarize the categories of Nen users... They are:
頑張れよ！　ゴン！ 釣り竿　持ってなくて 大丈夫か？ 手ぶらじゃ ヒソカは釣れねえぞ！ そして　ひときわ激しい炎を 巻き上げ　登場するのは？ ヒソカ選手だ！
Enhancers, Transmuters, Conjurers, Emitters, Manipulators, and Specialists, for a total of six categories.
この場所で繰り広げられた カストロ選手との死闘は
C-Categories...
現在９勝３敗！ 勝てば　フロアマスター 負ければ一転　地上落ち！
Every Nen user belongs to one of these.
しかし　リングに姿を見せれば いまだ負けなし！ 無敗神話は続くのか！
You want to increase the amount of your aura, as well as the speed of its flow.
あぁ… そんな目で見つめないでよ 興奮しちゃうじゃないか
In a battle between Nen users, those are the factors that... That...
ゴンくん　無理はよせよ
Th-that are pivotal in determining the victor.
ポイント＆ノックアウト制 時間無制限　１本勝負！ 始め！
In addition to the basic Nen
abilities Zetsu and Ren, there are also unique techniques that reflect
さぁ　注目の一戦！ 今　その戦いの火蓋が切られた！
the Nen user's individuality.
先に仕掛けるのは　どちらか！ ゴン選手だ！
If you develop a technique that synchronizes
with your style and Nen category, the manifestation of your ability has
a better chance of being stronger.
えっ!?
is the simplest
うわっ！
and most commonly used method.
クリーンヒット！ １ポイント　ヒソカ！
Since the water's overflowing, that makes you an Enhancer. An Enhancer?
す…　すさまじい攻防です！
Which confirms that Rammot is a Nen user? Seems so.
実況を差し挟む隙さえ ありませんでした！
Oh, yeah...
フフフ…　どうした？
Didn't you say you fought a rare human?
まだ僕は　開始位置から 動いてさえいないんだけどね。 えっ　ホントに？
Y-Yes. The impact from its attack opened your pores...
どひゃ！　クソ　見てろよ！
And released your aura. Pores?
よし　全部　当てるつもりで 攻撃するんじゃなくて
Apparently, they're small holes all over your body.
フェイントを交ぜると 効果があるんだな
If they're sealed, aura can't be released.
楽しんでやがるぜ ヒソカの野郎…
I see... Colt also thought that Rammot's change
やっぱり　実戦技術は 天と地の差だ
was triggered by his fight
with the rare humans.
でも　弱みはある
It seems he was correct.
ヒソカは自分が格上だと 自覚している だから逃げない そこに付け入る隙はある！
So if Rammot is a Nen user now, can we use him to open everyone's pores?
それなら…　あのてだ！
Sure, sounds good.
出た！ ゴン選手の「石板返し」！
The leaf wilted...
うりゃ！
Unbelievable.
石板を砕いて石つぶてに… ゴンは？
One of us was born possessing Nen ability, without having to fight a rare human!
どこだ？
Then, Commander, that makes you a Specialist, not belonging to another category?
しかし　この後 ヒソカの実力を思い知らされる 壮絶な激闘が 待っているのである
From birth, Neferpitou already
possessed incredible power.